Pedro Duarte Faria

Undergrad Student of Economics | Age 21

1021, Herculano Pena, Block B, Apartment 305, Salgado Filho, Belo Horizonte, MG - Brazil

Email: pedro.faria1@aluno.ufop.edu.br | Phone: +55 (31) 98512-4294

Personal website: https://pedro-faria.netlify.app/

Qualifications and personal characteristics ___

- My experiences and interests are related to the fields of data analysis, economics and programming.
- Most recently experiences and contributions involved the automation of various process, with the aid of programming.
- I have practical experience with SQL; I have proficiency at the R language; I have great experience with Excel; and I am currently learning the Python language.
- I can communicate in English. TOEFL ITP B2 level certificate, acquired at September of 2018.
- I am a very calm and introspective person, but still, a very creative one, that have great love for solving complex problems.

Education	
Federal University of Ouro Preto - UFOP	
B.A. Economics	March of 2017 - present
Conclusion expected for December of 2021.	
Federal University of Minas Gerais - UFMG	
Visiting Undergrad Student (Economics)	February of 2019 - November of 2020

Professional Experiences _

1. Intership at Statistics and Information Department, August of 2019-present

João Pinheiro Foundation (FJP) 1

My main responsibility at João Pinheiro Foudation is to calculate many indexes for a state law, that is traditionally called of The Robin Hood Law (Law 18.030/2009 - MG). But my main contribution for the institution is in the automation of various process, with the R programming language. Bringing greater efficiency to the workflow of many colleagues at the institution.

2. Internship on Business Inteligence, June of 2019-August of 2019.

Fideleasy ²

¹João Pinheiro Foundation is a research institution, founded in 1969. The institution have the purpose to provide research and knowledge to enhance public policy development and public management of Minas Gerais state government, located at Belo Horizonte-MG. Website: http://www.fjp.mg.gov.br/.

²Company of business management and consultancy services, located at Belo Horizonte-MG.

My main responsibility at Fideleasy, was to maintain the many profit and revenue indexes of our main client at the time, the Belgian financial institution BT Transfers. While I worked there, I developed two new performance indexes for *Compliance* and *BackOffice* sectors of the company. In addition to that, I developed a markup system capable of identifying the sales of the company that were made through WhatsApp.

Personal projects __

1. Book project, April of 2020 - January of 2020. *Concluded*.

FARIA, Pedro Duarte; PARGA, João Pedro Figueira Amorim. *Introdução à Linguagem R:* seus fundamentos e sua prática. 1. ed. Belo Horizonte: [s.n.], 2020. 440 p. ISBN 978-65-00-12606-8. Avaliable at: https://pedro-faria.netlify.app/pt/publication/book/introducao_linguagem_r/.

2. Course project, December of 2019 - present. *In development*.

Introductory Course for the R Language. The project was born during my work at João Pinheiro Foudation, and, at this point, it already had 2 editions. The first one, happened at João Pinheiro Foundation in the first semester of 2020, and the second one, occurred remotely (due to Covid-19 security measures) in November of 2020. The most recent edition was developed in conjunction with CORECON-MG³ Academic, and it reached students from 6 different countries.

3. Research project, September of 2019 - December of 2020. Concluded and accepted for publication.

FARIA, Pedro Duarte. Cooperação Universidade – Indústria no Brasil: suas características e desafios, a partir da PINTEC (2000-2017). *Revista Multiface*, Belo Horizonte, v. 9, n. 1, 2021. No prelo.

Academic Experiences ___

1. Volunteer Monitor, January of 2021 - present.

Monitor at the course Econometrics I. I am giving lessons to help students with difficulties to apply regression techniques to Economics.

Supervisor: Phd. Diogo Ferraz. Professor at DEECO/UFOP.

2. Scientific Research Initiation, February of 2018-February of 2019.

Here, me and my supervisor applied a Green Job index to the Minas Gerais (MG) state economy, with the purpose to find out how "green" this economy is.

Theme: "Sustainable Development on Minas Gerais: an analysis based on Green Jobs index".

Supervisor: Phd. Héder Carlos de Oliveira. Professor at DEECO/UFOP and PPEA/UFOP.

3. Conjecture Center, June of 2018-February of 2019.

A group research project, where me and my colleagues were trying to answer the question: "Why the brazilian interest rate is so high?". We reached the conclusion that the high concentration on brazilian bank market, was the main variable to explain this fact.

Supervisors: Phd. André Mourthé de Oliveira and Phd. Cristiane Márcia dos Santos. Both professors at

³Regional Economics Council of Minas Gerais.

DEECO/UFOP.

4. Volunteer Monitor, August of 2018-December of 2018.

Monitor at the course Mathematics for Economics II. I gave lessons to help students with difficulties to apply partial derivatives, optimization, differential equations and some others math tools to Economics.

Supervisor: Phd. Martin Harry Vargas Barrenechea. Professor at DEECO/UFOP and PPEA/UFOP.

Knowledge on programming languages and software _____

- 1. R programming language.
- 2. SQL.
- 3. Python language (basics).
- 4. Latex.
- **5.** QGis.
- 6. Microsoft Office and Power Bi.

Languages _____

- Portuguese (native).
- English (TOEFL ITP B2 level, September of 2018).

\sim			- 4	
	r	16	1 T	•
v		4	ıι	S.

Scientific Research Initiation Grant (R\$ 4800), February of 2018 - February of 2019.

FAPEMIG, Foundation for Research of the State of Minas Gerais.

Prize for presented research, November of 2020.

Event: XXI Seminário de Jovens Pesquisadores (SJP/UNESP), and I Seminário de Jovens Pesquisadores em Economia Industrial e Inovação (NEIT/IE/UNICAMP).

Research presented: Cooperação Universidade – Indústria no Brasil: suas características e desafios, a partir da PINTEC (2000-2017).

Annals of the event are avaliable at: https://geein.fclar.unesp.br/eventos/xxi-sei-e-i-sjp-publicacao-dos-artigos-e-resumos-nos-anais-do-evento.

First Experience ___

6. Consecon Jr⁴, June of 2017- June of 2018. Email: conseconjr@gmail.com

Projects advisor. Work as a volunteer with stock management at Prímula Cosmetics⁵, and as a writer of journalist articles about economics for the local journal, Ponto Final⁶.

Courses and Complementary Education _

⁴Junior Company of Economics in Federal University of Ouro Preto. We work with financial and management consultancy for companies at Mariana and Ouro Preto regions. Website: https://conseconjr.wixsite.com/conseconjr>.

⁵Little shop of cosmetics, located at Cachoeira Do Campo, Ouro Preto-MG.

⁶Journal company, located at São Pedro, Mariana-MG.

Course, January of 2018.

"Rudiments of Project Management" by Bradesco Foundation (59 hours).

Course, April of 2018.

"Data Analysis with Stata" at Federal University of Ouro Preto, Mariana, Brazil (8 hours).

Course, December of 2018.

"Microsoft Excel 2010" three courses of basic, intermediate and advanced levels, by Bradesco Foundation (41 hours).